Emile Berliner Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 16. Acoustic Tile, 1899, 1925-1929, 2.5 linear feet
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous N-O, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 37/7)
    - Peck, Stowe and Wilcox Co. (Pexto), 1927 (Box-folder 37/8)
    - Miscellaneous P, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 37/9)
    - Miscellaneous R, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 37/10)
    - Smoot, 1927 (Box-folder 37/11)
    - Sun Book and Job Printing Office, Frank Vinton, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 37/12)
    - Miscellaneous S, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 37/13)
    - Miscellaneous T, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 37/14)
    - Miscellaneous U-W, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 38/1)
    - Wolfe & Littlehales, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 38/2)
    - Miscellaneous Y-Z, 1899, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 38/3)
    - Unidentified, 1927 (Box-folder 38/4)
  - Clippings, 1927 and undated
    - February–March, 1927 (Box-folder 38/5)
    - April 1927 (Box-folder 38/6)
    - May 1927 (Box-folder 38/7)
    - June 1927 (Box-folder 38/8)
    - July–August, 1927 (Box-folder 38/9)
    - undated (Box-folder 38/10)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, undated (Box-folder 38/11)
- Series 17. Berliner Family Home Movie, 1903 or 1904, 1 film reel of 1 (12 feet): silent, black-and-white; 16 mm. nitrate
  Due to the non-standard frame size of the original nitrate material, the footage was "passed through" the printer four times in order to print all segments of the picture to a 16 mm. viewing print. For the online Berliner exhibit, the 16mm print was transferred to Betacam SP videotape to produce the master for digitization. Short jumps in continuity in the digital version indicate that small parts of the original film are missing.
  Like many other motion pictures of the time, the original film was probably shot with a variable speed camera. Therefore, in the video mastering process, the playback speed was adjusted to present the appearance of natural motion to the greatest degree possible.